Guide to the Kathleen George Papers, 1962-2014 CTC.2012.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence and Other Materials, 1964-2009; II.
  - ***Reader's report - Classic plays from the Negro Ensemble Company for the University of Pittsburgh Press, April 28, 1992
  - ***Reader's report - Directing Plays: A Working Professional's Method by Stuart Vaughan for Longman Publishing, October 7, 1991
  - ***Reader's report - Mayfield Publishing Company, 1995-1997
  - Three Rivers Lecture Series - Amy Tan biography, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Wandalie Henshaw - Information file (Box 22, Folder 21)
- Writing Career, 1961-2014; III.
  This series contains all the materials related to Kathleen George's literary works and creative writing. The series is divided into four subseries - Newspaper and magazine articles, Published Works, Unpublished works, and Writing related.
  - Newspaper and Magazine Articles, 1975-2012; 1.
    Contained in this section are essays, columns, reviews, etc. by Kathleen George in newspapers or magazines. The book reviews are mainly from the Pittsburgh City Paper or the Pittsburgh Post Gazette. George has published several essays or columns, the majority of which appeared in the Pittsburgh Post Gazette. Some were featured in the Books on Sunday section and are autobiographical in nature.
    - Book reviews, 1992-2012 (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    - Feature on Pittsburgh restaurants in George's novels Table Magazine, 2011 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper articles about George, 1998-2012 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Please see oversized series for more newspaper articles about George.
    - Newspaper articles by George, 1975-2012 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      Please see oversized series for more newspaper articles by George.
    - Theatre articles and reviews, 1979-1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Published Works, 1974-2006; 2.
    This subseries contains materials related to Dr. George's published short stories and monographs. The academic works, short story collections, and novels are arranged in chronological order by their publication date. Each title's files contains drafts, marketing materials, reviews, correspondence with the publisher, etc.
    - Published Short Fiction, 1979-2006
      - Story of a Male Anima, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 7)
        Story of a Male Anima was published in the March/April 1981 issue of Nit and Wit (#36-37).
      - Anagrams, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 8)
        Anagrams was published in the May 1981 issue of Wind Literary Journal (#41).
      - Country Tale, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 9)
        Country Tale was published in 1981 by Valhalla (vol. 7).
      - Too Much Woman, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 10-11)
        Too Much Woman was published in the March 1989 issue of Mademoiselle. The story was also published in Japan by the magazine Peach. The story's previous title was Martial Art.
      - Rusty's, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 11)
        Rusty's was published in the June 1989 issue of Oklawaha Review (Vol.1 no.1).
      - Dance at St. Theresa's (Box 24, Folder 1)
        Dance at St. Theresa's was published in the January 1990 issue of Cimarron Review (#90). It was also in Writing: the Translation of Memory edited by Eve Shellnut and published by Macmillan in 1990.
      - Flight, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 2)
        Flight was published in the Spring 1990 issue of Great Stream Review (Vol.2 no.1).
      - Rites of Burial, 1989-1992 (Box 24, Folder 3)
        Rites of Burial was published in the July 1990 issue of Cimarron Review (#92).
      - Good News, 1993 (Box 24, Folder 4)
        Good News was published in the Spring 1993 issue of Loyalhanna Review (Vol.2 no.2).
      - The Man in the Buick, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 5)
        The Man in the Buick, was published in the Spring 1993 issue of West Branch (No.31/32).
      - Things Progress, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 6)
        Things Progress was published in the July 1993 issue of Cimarron Review (No.104).
      - Sighting, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 7)
        Sighting was published in the Spring & Summer 1993 issue of Alaska Quarterly Review (Vol.11 no.3&4).
      - Weeds, 1992-1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
        Weeds was published in the 1993 issue of Gulf Stream Magazine (No.8).
      - Tractor Accident, 1993-1994 (Box 24, Folder 9)
        Tractor Accident was published in the March/April 1994 issue of North American Review (Vol.279 no.2).
      - Small Errands, 1988-1993 (Box 24, Folder 10)
        Small Errands was published in the Spring 1994 issue of Other Voices (No.20).
      - Chinese Massage, 1994 (Box 24, Folder 11)
        Tractor Accident was published in the Fall 1994 issue of West Branch (No.35).
      - Maria, 1994-1995 (Box 24, Folder 12)
        Maria was published in the Fall 1995 issue of American Fiction (Vol.7).
      - Weather Songs, 1995 (Box 24, Folder 13)
        Weather Songs was published in the Fall 1995 issue of Vignette (Vol.1 no.3).
      - An Actor Prepares, or Working Up the Part, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 14)
        An Actor Prepares was published in the May/June & July/August 1998 issue of North American Review (Vol.283 no.3&4). The story also received an honorable mention in the Salt Hill Journal's annual fiction contest.
      - Heartbreak House, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 15)
        Heartbreak House was published in the Fall 2000 issue of New Letters (Vol.67 no.1).
      - A Week in Summer, 2006 (Box 24, Folder 16)
        A Week in Summer was published 2006 by Amazon.com. The short story is available as part of the Amazon Shorts section of Amazon.
      - Chill (Box 24, Folder 17)
        Chill was published in the March 2010 issue of Spirit Magazine.
    - Rhythm in Drama, 1974-1982
      Rhythm in Drama was published by the University of Pittsburgh Press in 1980. This work was adapted from Dr. George's dissertation. In 1986, it was also published by the Shanghai Drama Institute in Chinese.
      - Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Dissertation - Abstract, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Dissertation - Correspondence and other files, 1974-1976 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Dissertation - Original copy, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Dissertation - Prospectus, August 1974 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Manuscript catalogue cards (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Permissions, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Publicity, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Playwriting: the First Workshop, 1991-2007
      Playwriting: The First Workshop was published by Focal Press in 1994. The text book replicates a workshop experience in developing playwriting skills.
      - Correspondence, 1991-1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence - Editing and proofs, 1992-1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Focal Press - Contract and rights, 1992,2007 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Permissions, 1989-1994 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Responses, 1992-2005 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Reviews, 1993-1995 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Submissions to other publishers, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - The Man in the Buick and Other Stories, 1995-2000
      The Man in the Buick and Other Stories was published in 1999 by the BkMk Press, in association with the University of Missouri-Kansas City. Nearly all of the short stories contained in the book had been previously published in various journals.
      - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence - BkMk Press, 1998-1999 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Draft (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Promotion and marketing, 1998-2000 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Proof (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Proof corrections - Individual pages (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Publisher pamphlet (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Publisher press kit, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Readings and appearances, 1998-2000 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Responses, 1999-2000 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Reviews, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Submissions to other publishers, 1995-1998 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Taken, 1999-2007
      The novel Taken was published by Delacorte Press in May of 2001. Drafts of this work were titled Pirate's Child. This is the first of several novels that center around the character of Pittsburgh Police detective Richard Christie.
      - Contracts, 2000-2002 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence - Publisher, 2001-2004 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Draft - Pre-copy edit (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Copy edited (Box 28, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - 2nd, January 2001 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Draft - Returned production copy, 2000-2001 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
      - Dust jacket design (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Mystery bookshop newsletters, 2001-2004 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Notes (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Publicity, 2000-2003 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Readings and appearances, 2001-2004 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2001-2007 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Submissions to other publishers, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Use in University of Pittsburgh English composition course, April 2006 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Fallen, 1999-2006
      The suspense novel Fallen was published in 2004 by Dell. Earlier versions of this work are titled Grief.
      - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Draft (Box 30, Folder 6-7)
      - Draft (Grief) (Box 31, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Copy edited with timeline, November 2003 (Box 31, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - First galleys, March 2004 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Incomplete, January 24, 2002 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Draft - Revised, June 2002 (Box 32, Folder 4-5)
      - Draft - Revised (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Second galleys, April 2004 (Box 33, Folder 3-4)
      - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 2003-2004 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Postcard, 2004 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Publicity, 2000-2004 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
      - Readings and appearances, 1999-2006 (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Research, 2001-2003 (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2004 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Winter's Tales: Reflections on the Novelistic Stage, 1994-2006
      Winter's Tales: Reflections on the Novelistic Stage was published in 2005 by the University of Delaware Press. This academic work examines the similarities between novels and plays that take place over a long time period.
      - Book launch, March 2006 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Book proposal - Unrevised (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Chapter summaries and introduction (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Commentary, 2003-2005 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Draft (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Draft (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Draft - Copy edited (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Draft - Copy edited, May 2004 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Incomplete Chapter one with corrections (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Draft - Incomplete Chapter two with notes (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Dust jacket design (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Galley proofs - First, December 13, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Galley proofs - Second, 2004-2005 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Notes (Box 37, Folder 6-7)
      - Notes, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Publicity, 2005-2006 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - References and index (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Research, 1994-1999 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Reviews (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Submissions to other publishers, 2000-2001 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - University of Delaware Press, 2000-2005 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Afterimage, 2004-2008
      Afterimage was published in 2007 by Thomas Dunne Books, an imprint of St. Martin's Press. Nearly all of the drafts of this work are titled Watched.
      - Author's questionnaire, October 14, 2006 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Draft (Watched) (Box 38, Folder 10-11)
      - Draft (Watched) (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (Watched) (Box 39, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft (Watched) (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (Watched), April 7, 2006 (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Copy edited, April 13, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - First galleys with corrections, June 5, 2007 (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Incomplete draft titled "Lies" (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Draft - Incomplete (Box 42, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Incomplete set of first galleys with different corrections, June 5, 2007 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Draft - With short story A Week in Summer (Box 42, Folder 4-5)
      - Notes (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Publicity, 2007-2008 (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - Readings and appearances, 2007-2008 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Research, 2004-2005 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2007-2008 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - The Odds, March 2007
      The Odds was published in 2009 by Thomas Dunne Books, an imprint of St. Martin's Press. The book was nominated for an Edgar Allen Poe award for best novel of the year by the Mystery Writers of America. Drafts of this work are titled Kids or Hooked.
      - Amazon preview, 2008 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence, March 8, 2007 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Draft (Hooked) (Box 43, Folder 8-9)
      - Draft (Hooked) (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (Box 44, Folder 3-5)
      - Draft (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Copy edited (Box 45, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft (Kids) - Early work copy (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - First galleys, February 2009 (Box 46, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Fragment (Box 46, Folder 5)
      - Draft - Trimmed (missing pgs. 335-358), November 2008 (Box 47, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (Kids) - Work copy (Box 48, Folder 1-2)
      - Edgar Allan Poe award nomination, 2010 (Box 48, Folder 3)
        Please see oversized series for the certificate of nomination.
      - Publicity, 2008-2011 (Box 48, Folder 4)
      - Readings and appearances, 2008-2011 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Research, 2002-2008 (Box 48, Folder 6)
      - Research, 2002-2008 (Box 49, Folder 1-2)
      - Responses (Box 49, Folder 3)
      - Reviews, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Pittsburgh Noir, 2004-2012
      Pittsburgh Noir was published in June 2011 by Akashic Books. The work is a part of the popular Akashic noir series. Kathleen George contributed a short story in addition to editing the book.
      - Akashic noir series clippings, 2004-2009 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Contributors, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence - Publisher, August 30, 2010 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - Draft (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
      - Draft - Duplex by Stewart O'Nan (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - Draft - Fragment (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Draft - When Johnny Came Shuffling Home by K.C. Constantine, 2010 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Publicity, 2011-2012 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Readings and appearances, 2011 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2011-2012 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Hideout, 2001-2011
      The suspense novel Hideout was published in August 2011 by Minotaur Books. Earlier versions of this work are titled Old Bird.
      - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - Draft (The Old Bird) (Box 50, Folder 7-8)
      - Draft - Copy edited (Box 50, Folder 9-10)
      - Draft - First galleys, December 14, 2010 (Box 51, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (The Old Bird) - Revised (Box 51, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Revised (Box 51, Folder 5-6)
      - Draft (The Old Bird) - Revised, June 2008 (Box 52, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Revised, May 13, 2010 (Box 52, Folder 3-4)
      - Dust jacket design (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Publicity, 2011 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Readings and appearances, 2011-2012 (Box 53, Folder 1)
      - Research, 2001-2008 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2011 (Box 53, Folder 3)
      - Style sheets (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Simple, 2011
      Simple was published in 2012 by Minotaur Books.
      - Blog posts (Box 53, Folder 5)
      - Chapter outlines (Box 53, Folder 6)
      - Characters (Box 53, Folder 7)
      - Draft (Box 53, Folder 8-9)
      - Draft - Copy edited (Box 54, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Fragment only pages 236-420 (Box 54, Folder 3)
      - Draft - First galleys with corrections, December 2011 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
      - Dust jacket copy (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - Publicity, 2012 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Readings and appearances, 2012 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - Research, 2009 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2012 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - A Measure of Blood, 1999-2014
      A Measure of Blood was published by MysteriousPress.com. It was released on January 14, 2014. Prior to publication, this work was titled And So I'm Leaving.
      - Acknowledgement (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Draft (Titled And So I'm Leaving) (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
      - Draft (Titled And So I'm Leaving) (Box 56, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Fragment with corrections (Box 56, Folder 3)
      - Draft - Fragment with corrections, June 21, 2011 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 56, Folder 5-6)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 57, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 57, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - Galley proofs, September 10, 2013 (Box 57, Folder 5-6)
      - Dust jacket (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Line edits, May 30, 2013 (Box 58, Folder 2)
      - Notes and chapter summaries, 2010 (Box 58, Folder 3)
      - Publicity (Box 58, Folder 4)
      - Readings and appearances, 2014 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      - Research, 1999-2009 (Box 58, Folder 6)
      - Reviews and other clippings, 2014 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - The Johnstown Girls, 1989-2014
      The Johnstown Girls was published by the University of Pittsburgh Press. It was released on April 1, 2014. Kathleen George's goal of writing a novel involving the Johnstown Flood was started about twenty-five years earlier. The drafts of that earlier work are in the Johnstown Stories section of the Unpublished Works subseries.
      - Character family tree (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Draft (News of the Flood), June 28, 2007 (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
      - Draft (Box 58, Folder 11-12)
      - Draft (Box 59, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 59, Folder 4-5)
      - Draft - With corrections and notes to assistants (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - With Christie character (Box 60, Folder 3-4)
      - Draft - With Christie character (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Draft - With possible illustrations (Box 61, Folder 1-2)
      - Notes, 2011-2013 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      - Publicity (Box 61, Folder 4)
      - Readings and appearances, 2014 (Box 61, Folder 5)
      - Research, 1989-2012 (Box 62, Folder 1-3)
      - Research - A True History of the Johnstown Flood Goodman production draft of the play by Rebecca Gilman, March 22, 2010 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      - Reviews and other clippings, February 2014 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished Works, 1961-2001; 3.
    This subseries contains materials related to Dr. George's un-published works. The subseries are arranged in alphabetical order by title. Each title's files contains drafts, research materials, etc.
    - Break, Heart, 1983
      - Draft - Handwritten (Box 62, Folder 6-7)
      - Draft - Incomplete (Box 62, Folder 8)
      - Draft (Nightly Awakenings) - Incomplete, 1983 (Box 62, Folder 9)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Draft - With corrections, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 2)
      - Draft - With corrections, 1983 (Box 63, Folder 3)
      - Dramatic version (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Journal style version (Box 63, Folder 5-6)
    - Feast Days, 1991-1999
      This unfinished novel is an expansion of the published short story Too Much Woman. The work also sometimes referred to or titled after its main character Willa or Willa, the Way She Dances.
      - Draft (Willa) (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Draft, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 2-3)
      - Draft, May 1993 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Draft, 1993 (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
      - Draft - Chapter ten, 1999 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      - Draft (Planetary Influence), 1996-1998 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      - Draft - Chapter one, six, and ten, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      - Draft - Chapters ten through seventeen, 1999 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      - Draft - First person, 1993 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      - Draft - Handwritten with notes (Box 66, Folder 2)
      - Draft - Handwritten with notes and research, 1991-1993 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      - Draft - With notes, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
      - Draft - With revision notes, 1992 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      - Submissions to publishers, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - 50 Cross-purposes Improvs for Actors and "The Improv, the Actor, the Writer, the Plot"
      Please see related improvisation materials in the Teaching subseries of the first series.
      - Draft (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Draft (Box 67, Folder 2)
      - Draft (Box 67, Folder 3)
      - Draft - Incomplete with corrections (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Draft - With corrections (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Draft - Writers section expanded (Box 67, Folder 6)
      - Presentation (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Getaway, 2000-2001
      Parts of this unpublished novel were incorporated into the Odds.
      - Incomplete draft with notes and research, 2000-2001 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      - Research, 2000-2001 (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
    - Johnstown Stories, 1989-1995
      Kathleen George began a project to write a story related to the Johnstown Flood as its two hundredth anniversary approached. The anniversary passed and she continued to work and re-work the project over the next twenty plus years. Sometimes the work was simply titled Johnstown Stories, other times as Birth Offerings. In 2014, The Johnstown Girls was published by the University of Pittsburgh Press. The book's release coincided with the Flood's two hundred and twenty fifth anniversary. For drafts and other materials of The Johnstown Girls see the novel's section in the Published Works subseries.
      - Draft (Birth Offerings) (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Draft (Birth Offerings) (Box 68, Folder 4-5)
      - Drafts - Incomplete handwritten drafts and outlines (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - Notes (Box 69, Folder 2)
      - Research, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      - Submissions to publishers, 1989-1995 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Rites of Burial, 1998-1998
      Rites of Burial was Kathleen George's first attempt to collect several of short stories into one publication. Early drafts of this work are titled Birth Offerings.
      - Adaptations of short stories (Box 69, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      - Draft - Annotated collection of short stories (Box 69, Folder 7)
      - Draft - Annotated collection of short stories, 1988 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      - Draft - Annotated collection of short stories, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 9)
      - Drafts (Birth Offerings) - Incomplete and handwritten (Box 69, Folder 10-11)
      - Notes (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Saloon Society, 1980-1981
      Kathleen George adapted this play from the book of the same name. The book itself was written by and related to Bill Manville's Village Voice columns.
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - Draft (Box 70, Folder 2)
      - Draft (Box 70, Folder 3)
      - Music, 1 cassette_tape (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - Notes and research, 1980-1981 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Short Fiction
      many of these are not dated
      - A-B, 1980-1983 (Box 70, Folder 6-7)
      - B-C, 1980-2014 (Box 71, Folder 1-5)
      - D-K, 1979-1983 (Box 72, Folder 1-9)
      - L-P, 1983-1994 (Box 73, Folder 1-5)
      - R-W, 1979-1985 (Box 74, Folder 1-6)
      - Unidentified or In progress (Box 74, Folder 7-9)
    - A Tony Story, 1983
      Tony's Story is an unfinished work of children's literature.
      - Correspondence with outline and sketches (Box 75, Folder 1)
      - Short story, 1983 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Undergraduate and Graduate writing and other materials, 1961-1964